Finding Aid for Galens Medical Society records, 1914-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Funds 1952-1990
  - Balance Sheets (all funds) (Box 6)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 6)
  - Children's Fund
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 6)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence
    - 1952, 1973-1977 (Box 6)
    - 1978 (Box 6)
    - 1979-1986 (Box 6)
  - General Fund
    - 1961-1976 (Ledger) (Box 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 6)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Kretzschmar Memorial Fund 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Kyselka Memorial Fund 1976-1990 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Petty Cash 1975-1977 (Box 6)
  - Student Loan Fund 1982-1990 (Box 6)
  - University Fund
    - 1980-1981 (Box 6)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 6)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - University Investment Pool Account (UIPA)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 6)
- Service Activities 1974-1992
  The Service Activities, 1974-1992 (1.0 linear ft.), series includes correspondence, annual reports, pamphlets and other miscellaneous material related to the allocation of funds by the Galens Financial Allocation Committee to children's charities in and around the University and Washtenaw County Communities. Materials include letters from non-profit and charitable organizations to Galens requesting funding for programs, activities and equipment as well as replies from Galens pertaining to these requests. Also included are reports and statements outlining how granted funds plan to be or have been used by these organizations.
  - Alpha House 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Ann Arbor Childcare and Development Center 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Ann Arbor Department of Parks and Recreation 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Arbor House 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Assault Crisis Center 1990 (Box 7)
  - Association for Care of Children's Health 1990 (Box 7)
  - Bryant Neighborhood Clinic 1980, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Camp Champ 1986-1988 (Box 7)
  - Camp Onkoi Benek 1978 (Box 7)
  - Catholic Social Services undated (Box 7)
  - Center for Eating Disorders 1987 (Box 7)
  - Child and Family Service of Washtenaw County 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Child Protection Team 1982 (Box 7)
  - Children's Psychiatric Hospital 1975-1989 (Box 7)
  - Community Action on Substance Abuse (CASA) 1982 (Box 7)
  - Comprehensive Education Program 1990 (Box 7)
  - Corner Cottage Child Care Center (Veterans Administration) 1979-1980, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Corner Health Center 1980-1992 (Box 7)
  - Cystic Fibrosis Foundation 1984 (Box 7)
  - Eberwhite PTO Playground 1990 (Box 7)
  - Family Support Program 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Father Patrick Jackson House 1988 (Box 7)
  - Free to Speak 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Galens Workshop 1979-1990 (Box 7)
  - Green Glacier Community Center 1990 (Box 7)
  - Hands-On Museum 1981-1990 (Box 7)
  - Headstart Program 1983 (Box 7)
  - Hemodialysis Unit 1980-1989 (Box 7)
  - Hemophilia of Michigan 1977-1985 (Box 7)
  - Holden Visiting Parents Group 1978-1982 (Box 7)
  - Hospice of Washtenaw 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - Lamaze Childbirth Preparation Association 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - Mercywood Neuro-Psychiatric Hospital Adolescent Program 1982-1987 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Human Services 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Society for Autistic Children (MSAC) 1980-1986 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Financial Allocations Committee 1975-1979 (Box 7)
  - Requests for Funding
    - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 7)
    - 1980-1990 (Box 7)
  - Mott Emergency Fund 1976-1987 (Box 7)
  - Mott Hospital (General) 1977, 1988 undated (Box 7)
  - Mott Music Therapy 1979, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - National Institute for Burn Medicine 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Neuro-Psychiatric Institute Adolescent Day Treatment Program 1974-1984 (Box 7)
  - Packard Community Clinic 1975-1989 (Box 7)
  - Patient Family Assistance Fund 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Peace Neighborhood Center 1980 (Box 7)
  - Pebble Creek Day Treatment Program 1978-1985 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Ambulatory Care 1980, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Cardiology 1978, 1983, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Hematology 1975-1988 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Neurology 1984-1986 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Oncology 1984 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Surgery Christmas Party 1986-1990 (Box 7)
  - Pediatric Walk-In Clinic 1978-1981 (Box 7)
  - Peoples Community Hospital Authority (PCHA) 1985 (Box 7)
  - Perry Nursery School 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - Frieda Poore 1980 (Box 7)
  - Project SAGE 1988 (Box 7)
  - Prospect Place Family Shelter 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - SAFE House 1978-1989 (Box 7)
  - SHARE 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Southeast Michigan Health Association 1991 (Box 7)
  - St. Joseph Mercy Hospital, Pediatrics Unit 1974-1984 (Box 7)
  - Student Parent Centers 1980-1988 (Box 7)
  - Students Teaching AIDS to Students (STATS) 1990 (Box 7)
  - Summit Medical Center 1976-1977, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Therapeutic Riding Inc. 1990 (Box 7)
  - Tot Drop, Inc. 1981, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Turner Geriatric Clinic 1980-1984 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw Association for Retarded Citizens 1983-1989 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw Camp Placement Association 1980-1983 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Community Mental Health Center Residential Services 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Health Department 1985-1990 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Special Olympics 1985 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw Interagency Coordinating Council for Infants & Toddlers 1990 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw Literacy 1990, 1991 undated (Box 7)
  - Wayne County Pediatrics 1979 (Box 7)
  - Wolverine Human Services 1990 (Box 7)
  - York Woods Center 1983 (Box 7)
- Smoker 1974-1992
  - Account Summary (Box 8)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 8)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Advertising Reports 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence 1990-1994 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1983-1994 (includes photographs) (Box 8)
  - Producer Reports
    - 1966 (Box 8)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - 1981-1984 (Box 8)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 8)
    - 1988, 1990, 1991, 1993 (Box 8)
    - 1994-1997 (Box 8)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 8)
  - Production Flyers and Tickets 1976-2015 (scattered) (Box 8)
  - Programs
    - 1951, 1970-1993 (scattered), 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1980, 1994, 1996, 1997, 2005, 2015 (Box 8)
  - Songbook undated (Box 8)
  - Scripts
    - "M*I*C*H," 1971 (Box 8)
    - "My Fair Malady," 1976 (Box 8)
    - "The Wizard of Gauze," 1978 (Box 8)
    - "The Sound of Mucus," 1980 (Box 8)
    - "O. Liver," 1981 (Box 8)
    - "Med Sci Story," 1983 (Box 8)
    - "Charlie and the Doctor Factory," 1991 (Box 8)
    - "Enema House," 1992, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - "The Little Dermaid," 1993, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - "Star Wards," 1994 (Box 8)
    - "Peter Pannus" (technical script) 1995 (Box 8)
    - "Little Marfan Annie" (technical script) 1996 (Box 8)
    - "How to Succeed in Medical School," 1997 (Box 8)
    - "Back to the Suture," 1999 (Box 8)
    - "Joseph and the Amazing Monocolor Whitecoat," 2000 (Box 8)
    - "Revenge of the GERD," 2005 (Box 8)
    - "Orifice Space," 2006 (Box 8)
    - "Spleen Girls," 2011 (Box 8)
    - "Bruit and the Beast,"2015 (Box 8)
Related Material
For related material researchers should see the Child and Family Department (University of Michigan) records 1922-2001. The Child and Family Life Department includes records of the Hospital School and has photographs and reports relating to Galens activities with the Hospital School and an arts and crafts program initiated by Galens.